Here is the PRD XML document for the Task Management App:

```xml
<productRequirementsDocument>
    <title>PRD for Task Management App</title>
    <executiveSummary>A comprehensive task management system for teams, enabling collaboration, task delegation, and task prioritization.</executiveSummary>
    <scope>
        <inScope>A list of features in scope for the MVP, including task creation, assignment, prioritization, and deletion.</inScope>
        <outOfScope>A list of features explicitly out of scope, including advanced reporting and analytics.</outOfScope>
    </scope>
    <businessGoals>
        <goal>Improve team productivity and efficiency</goal>
        <goal>Enhance collaboration and communication among team members</goal>
        <goal>Reduce task complexity and improve task management</goal>
    </businessGoals>
    <useCases>
        <useCaseModel>
            <useCase id="UC-001">
                <title>Create Task</title>
                <description>A user creates a new task in the task management app, including task details such as title, description, and due date.</description>
                <actors>
                    <actor>User</actor>
                </actors>
                <preconditions>User is logged in and has permission to create tasks</preconditions>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User enters task title and description</step>
                    <step>User selects due date</step>
                    <step>User saves task</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternateFlows/>
                <postconditions>Task is created and displayed in the task list</postconditions>
                <priority>high</priority>
                <businessValue>Allows users to create new tasks and prioritize their work</businessValue>
            </useCase>
            <useCase id="UC-002">
                <title>Assign Task</title>
                <description>A user assigns a task to another user in the task management app, including assigning task details such as due date and responsible user.</description>
                <actors>
                    <actor>User</actor>
                </actors>
                <preconditions>User is logged in and has permission to assign tasks</preconditions>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User selects task to assign</step>
                    <step>User enters responsible user and due date</step>
                    <step>User saves assignment</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternateFlows/>
                <postconditions>Task is assigned to the responsible user and displayed in their task list</postconditions>
                <priority>high</priority>
                <businessValue>Enables collaboration and task delegation among team members</businessValue>
            </useCase>
            <useCase id="UC-003">
                <title>Prioritize Task</title>
                <description>A user prioritizes a task in the task management app using AI-powered algorithms, including selecting task priority and due date.</description>
                <actors>
                    <actor>User</actor>
                </actors>
                <preconditions>User is logged in and has permission to prioritize tasks</preconditions>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User selects task to prioritize</step>
                    <step>User selects priority and due date</step>
                    <step>User saves priority</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternateFlows/>
                <postconditions>Task is prioritized and displayed in the task list with updated priority</postconditions>
                <priority>high</priority>
                <businessValue>Improves task management and reduces task complexity</businessValue>
            </useCase>
            <useCase id="UC-004">
                <title>View Task Details</title>
                <description>A user views task details in the task management app, including task title, description, and due date.</description>
                <actors>
                    <actor>User</actor>
                </actors>
                <preconditions>User is logged in and has permission to view task details</preconditions>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User selects task to view</step>
                    <step>Task details are displayed</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternateFlows/>
                <postconditions>Task details are displayed and user can take actions</postconditions>
                <priority>medium</priority>
                <businessValue>Provides users with task information and enables them to take actions</businessValue>
            </useCase>
            <useCase id="UC-005">
                <title>Delete Task</title>
                <description>A user deletes a task in the task management app, including deleting task details such as title and due date.</description>
                <actors>
                    <actor>User</actor>
                </actors>
                <preconditions>User is logged in and has permission to delete tasks</preconditions>
                <mainFlow>
                    <step>User selects task to delete</step>
                    <step>User confirms deletion</step>
                    <step>Task is deleted</step>
                </mainFlow>
                <alternateFlows/>
                <postconditions>Task is deleted and displayed as deleted</postconditions>
                <priority>high</priority>
                <businessValue>Removes unnecessary tasks and improves task management</businessValue>
            </useCase>
        </useCaseModel>
    </useCases>
    <nonFunctionalRequirements>
        <requirement type="Security">All sensitive data must be encrypted at rest and in transit using industry-standard protocols.</requirement>
        <requirement type="Performance">The system must respond to 95% of user queries in under 2 seconds.</requirement>
    </nonFunctionalRequirements>
</productRequirementsDocument>
```

This PRD XML document includes the following sections:

*   `title`: The title of the PRD document.
*   `executiveSummary`: A brief summary of the project's purpose and scope.
*   `scope`: A list of features in scope for the MVP and features explicitly out of scope.
*   `businessGoals`: A list of business goals for the project.
*   `useCases`: A list of use cases for the project, including their descriptions, actors, preconditions, main flows, alternate flows, postconditions, priorities, and business values.
*   `nonFunctionalRequirements`: A list of non-functional requirements for the project, including security and performance requirements.

Note that this is a sample PRD XML document and may need to be modified to fit the specific needs of your project.